A Guide to the Virginia Tech Dairy Science Complex Records, c. 1948-1968
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Virginia Tech Dairy Science Complex Records, c. 1948-1968
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 13/8/1
6.2 Cubic Feet; 13 boxes
The contents from this collection are somewhat smelly and dirty. The original covers have been removed for preservation purposes, and the contents are separated into folders. In some cases, they are subdivided with sheets of acid-free paper.
The Virginia Tech Dairy Science Complex Records, RG 13/8/1, contains ledgers from the Dairy Science Department's farm which was originally located near Southgate Rd. There are 23 ledgars in this record that include information about breeding records, calfing, feeding records, pedigrees, and the general health of VPI's diary cows. Some ledgars include certificates and awards from the VT Dairy Science Complex. The majority of the records from the Dairy Sceince Complex date from 1948 to 1969; however, some documents date back to 1916.
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Department of Dairy Science
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Virginia Tech Dairy Sceince Complex Records were transferred to Special Collections in July 2015.
Historical Note
The Virginia Tech Dairy Science Complex is run by the Department of Dairy Science in the College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, a founding college of the university when it opened in 1872. The original Dairy Complex was located near Southgate Road before being moved for expansion in 2015. The new VT Dairy Science Complex is located on Ketland Farm, a 35 acre research site in the Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station.
Scope and Content
The Virginia Tech Dairy Sceince Complex, RG 13/8/1, contains ledgers about the dairy herds in the Department of Dairy Science farms from 1948 to 1969. The ledgers include information about breeding records, calfing, feeding records, pedigrees, and general health of cattle. Some ledgers include certificates and awards from the VT Dairy Science Complex.
Index Terms
Subjects:
University History; University Archives; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Department of Dairy Science; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. College of Agriculture and Life Sciences
Contents List
- Brown Swiss Registration of Certificates, 1958, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Breeding Record, 1947-1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Herd Record Book, 1961-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Herd Record Book, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Monthly Dairy Herd Records - Jerseys, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Strathglass Farm, Health Current, Vol. 1, 1951-1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- College Holsteins, 1942-1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Private Herd Book - Guernseys, 1919-1946 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Record of Service of the Herd, 1916-1946 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Herd Record Book, 1958-1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Awards and Certificates, 1930-1956 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station - Ayrshire Herd and Out of Herd, 1950-1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station Herd - Holstein, 1958-1968 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station Herd Record, 1943-1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- College Herd Record Book, 1945-1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Out of Herd - Holsteins, 1943-1965 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Out of Herd - Guernseys, 1948-1968 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Herd Record Book - Guernseys, 1935-1962 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Out of Herd - Holsteins, 1949-1967 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Out of Herd - Holsteins, 1930-1960 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station - Out of Herd - Holsteins, 1957-1965 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Out of Herd - University Brown Swiss, 1946-1967 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Out of Herd, 1916-1959 (Box 13, Folder 1)